Inventory of the James Barron Papers (1) 1776-1899
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Box 12, n.d. (Box-folder 12:1-87)
  There are 15 drafts of letters by James Barron, 11 estimates, accounts, and the like and 44 other pieces of manuscript material including: a list of writings by Barron; several articles on the plans for the reorganization of the Navy Department; one each on the defense of the coasts, steamboats, telegraphic communications, the influx of foreigners; an application for the extension of his patents and a claim for injuries, two accounts of events in the War of Independence, A Short History of the Frigate Alliance, and an untitled poem; a six page "Extract from a letter to the Secretary of State of the United States" concerning the war with Tripoli and a discussion of his difficulties with Commo. Rodgers which almost ended in a duel; and an extract from the logbook of the Chesapeake.
  - Undated Letters, Invitations, etc. received by Commodore James Barron, n.d. (Box-folder 12:1-35)
    - Invitation from Pres. and Mrs. Adams to Capt. Barron, for dinner, n.d., PADS. (Box-folder 12:1)
    - Amicus Justicia, pseudonym, to Commo. James Barron, Norfolk, Virginia, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:2)
      Re: Dr. Thos. G. Peachy of Williamsburg who reported that Capt. Gordon (of the U.S. Ship Chesapeake at the time of The Chesapeake-Leopard Affair) felt that Barron was "an injured man."
    - Chester Bailey, Mansion House, to Commo. Barron, Phila., n.d. Monday., ALS. (Box-folder 12:3)
      Request for the loan of a "Handsome Flag" for the visit of Gen. Lafayette.
    - Invitation from Commo. Bainbridge, Williamsburg, [Virginia], to Commo. Barron, U.S. Navy, for dinner, 4 August n.y., AL. (Box-folder 12:4)
    - Commo. Bainbridge, [Phila.] to Commo. Barron, Walnut St. [Phila.], n.d., AL. (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Dr. P[hilip] Barraud, to Commo. Barron, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:6)
      Re: an illness of the daughter of Barron.
    - G. Bermard, [New York], to Commo. Barron, U.S. Navy, New York, 11 July n.y., AL. (Box-folder 12:7)
    - W.C[raig] to Commo. James Barron, Norfolk, Virginia, [1821]., ALS. (Box-folder 12:8)
      Personal letter.
    - Announcement of a "Tribute of Respect" for Mr. Henry Eckford, to Commo. James Barron, Navy Yard, Norfolk, Virginia, 2 July n.y., PM. (Box-folder 12:9)
    - Jno. McElroy to Commo. Barron, Philadelphia, February n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:10)
      Re. the washing machine invented by Barron.
    - Undated letters from J.D. Elliott to James Barron, n.d., 12 letters. AlsS. (Box-folder 12:11)
    - D.G. Farragut, U.S. Ship Erie, to Commo. James Barron, n.d., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:12)
      A comparison of the advances of the French Navy over the practices of the American and English navies.
    - G. Galt to Commo. Barron, 4 July n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:13)
      Re: a letter to Mr. Thompson.
    - Undated letters from T. Gatewood to James Barron, n.d., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 12:14)
    - Wm. Gatewood to Commo. James Barron, n.d., PAMS. (Box-folder 12:15)
      A printed broadsheet, Highly important to Commerce and the Navigation of the Pacific.
    - J. Gibbons to Commo. Barron, Hampton, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:16)
      Re: D.M. Randolph.
    - Dr. Gillespy to Commo. Barron, 21 March n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:17)
      An invitation.
    - Thomas Glenn to Commo. James Barron, Navy Yard, Gosport, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:18)
      Re: An enclosed bill.
    - S.W. Godon, Philadelphia, to James Barron, Norfolk, 29 March n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:19)
      Re: business matters. Endorsement re: "Lieut. Godon."
    - Chas. W. Goldsborough, to Commo. Barron, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:20)
      Introducing his brother.
    - An invitation from Mrs. Greland to Commo. Barron, Spruce St., [Phila.], n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:21)
    - Francis Grive to James Barron, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:22)
      Re: the repairs on the ship Constellation.
    - Undated letters from Capt. John Gwinn, Navy Yard, to Commo. James Barron, n.d., 6 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 12:23)
    - Invitation from Dr. Hare to Commo. Barron. 19 October n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:24)
    - Invitation from [President] Harrison to Commo. Barron, Saturday the 19th, n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:25)
    - Capt. Beverley Kennon to Commo. Barron, Wednesday, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:26)
      Re: Barron's bride.
    - Capt. Edm. P. Kennedy to Commo. Barron, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:27)
      Re: Commo. Rodgers and a procession.
    - Invitation from General Macomb to Commo. Barron, U.S. Navy, 22 July n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:28)
    - Capt. J. MacKeever, Navy Yard, Gosport, to Commo. James Barron, Washington, 20 November, n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:29)
      Re: affairs at the Navy Yard.
    - Morris Myers to Commo. Barron, Navy Yard, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:30)
      Re: "two pieces of timber."
    - Francis Page to Commo. James Barron, Norfolk, n.d., ALS. (Box-folder 12:31)
      Enquiry about the activities of Gen'l Thomas Nelson in the Revolutionary War, made by the son of Gov. John Page. Reply of to be directed in care of Thos. N. Page in Richmond.
    - Rich'd E. Parker, Norfolk, to [James Barron], 24 December n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:32)
      Re: General Taylor and the defense of Coney Island.
    - Invitations from the President to Commo. Barron, n.d., PADS. (Box-folder 12:33)
      Three invitations to dinner (the President is not named).
    - The Chevalier De Tacon to Commo. Barron, Brown's Hotel, [?], 31 January n.y., AL. (Box-folder 12:34)
      Re: dimensions of a barge and dining bell.
    - Lt. Wm. Tazewell to Commo. Barron, 26 June n.y., ALS. (Box-folder 12:35)
      Introducing John Ambler.
  - Letters and Drafts of Letters sent by Commodore James Barron, n.d. (Box-folder 12:37-50)
    - [James Barron] to Tho. Broughton, Norfolk, 28 July n.y., ADr. (Box-folder 12:37)
    - [James Barron] to Dr. Hermann, introducing Dr. Harris, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:38)
    - J[ames] B[arron] to Moffatt and Law, n.d., ADrS. 2 drafts on one sheet. (Box-folder 12:39)
    - J[ames] B[arron] "To a Member of Congress respecting Mid'n Henderson Williams," n.d., ADrS. (Box-folder 12:40)
    - [James Barron] to Alexander Porter, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:41)
    - [James Barron] to James Rammage, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:42)
    - [James Barron] to James Ronaldson, Pres. of the Faculty of the Franklin Institute, Philadelphia, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:43)
    - J[ames] B[arron] to the Secretary of the Navy respecting Lyman Law, n.d., ADrS. (Box-folder 12:44)
    - [James Barron] to the Secretary of the Navy. Re: "on poppy seed," n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:45)
    - [James Barron] to the Secretary of the Navy. Re: "on change of stations," n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:46)
    - [James Barron] to Mr. Thompson, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:47)
    - [James Barron] to John Thompson, Richmond, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:48)
    - [James Barron] to Purser Thornton, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:49)
    - J[ames] B[arron] to [?], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:50)
  - Manuscripts written by, or preserved by Commodore James Barron, n.d. (Box-folder 12:51-81)
    - A statement, n.d., AD. (Box-folder 12:51)
      Re: "Inventions and essays on Naval Subjects by Commodore James Barron...."
    - Papers addressed to Commo. James Barron and written by him, n.d., 8 items. ADrs. (Box-folder 12:52)
      Re: the reorganization of the Board of Navy Commissioners.
    - On "Telegraph" or "Rapid intercourse between distant places by sound or vision" [by James Barron], n.d., 7 pages. ADr. (Box-folder 12:53)
      Also enclosed are drawings of telegraph positions. 3 pages.
    - Item concerns a system of signals, based on those written by [James Barron] in 1798-99, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:54)
    - Item concerns the considerations of "the Board" in the defense of the coasts of Virginia [in the War of 1812], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:55)
    - Item concerns "steam boats" from early experiments made in 1784 or 1785 [by James Barron], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:56)
    - Item concerns the Naval defense of Philadelphia [by James Barron], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:57)
    - A letter to an editor [by James Barron], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:58)
      Re: the need for a school ship to train Americans.
    - "Memorandum of my Business before Congress" [by James Barron], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:59)
      Extension of patents, remuneration for code signals, ventilators and prow ships, claim for father's bounty land vs. the claims of John Thompson.
    - A claim for injuries received in 1798, 1799, and 1800, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:60)
    - "The Patriot and Capt. Starlius," a Revolutionary War account [by James Barron], n.d., 5 pages. ADr. (Box-folder 12:61)
    - "Transactions in Virginia" in the Revolutionary War, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:62)
      Lord Dunmore is mentioned.
    - "A Short History of the Continental Frigate Alliance," n.d., 5 pages. AV. (Box-folder 12:63)
    - Item concerns military maneuvers, n.d., AD. (Box-folder 12:64)
    - Item concerns "rape seed." n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:65)
    - A poem, unsigned and untitled, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:66)
    - "Extract from a letter to the Hon'ble Secretary of State of the United States," n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:67)
      Re: "the Raise and Capt. Egery in Tripoli."
    - Item concerns Capt. Rodgers and Commo. Barron, n.d., 2 items. ADr. (Box-folder 12:68)
    - Item concerns Commo. Stewart, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:69)
    - Item concerns Colonel Cropper and Commo. Haley, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:70)
    - Item concerns Mr. Drayton, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:71)
    - "Indecent and disrepectful conduct on the part of G.K. towards J[ames] B[arron]," n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:72)
    - "Original documents in Reply to Miles King" [by James Barron], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:73)
    - Item concerns Mr. Armstead's testimony on the ship Portia in Denmark and Mr. Laakie, U.S. Consul in Copenhagen, [by James Barron], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:74)
    - Port directions, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:75)
    - "Narrative, War for Independence," n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:76)
      Re: Allen McLane.
    - Item concerns "The Case of France and the U. States" in opposition to the opinion of Mr. Tazewell, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:77)
    - Largely illegible, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:78)
    - "From Polybius upon Ancient Ships," n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:79)
    - A sketch of a portion of the Baltic Sea and northern German lands, n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:80)
    - An address to "Young Ladies," n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 12:81)
      Re: Susan B. Anthony.
  - Accounts, Lists and the Like, n.d. (Box-folder 12:82-87)
    - Two account sheets, n.d., 2 items. AD. (Box-folder 12:82a)
      Endorsement: "A Memorandum showing the difference between the price asked and that paid for building a Carriage House."
    - Statement about "Materials for a boat 10 by 15." n.d., AD. (Box-folder 12:82g)
    - "The relative value of wood & coal as an article of fuel on board Ships of War," n.d., AD. (Box-folder 12:83)
    - "Estimate for a floating dock to contain a Frigate of 1st class," signed Wm P. Asisy, n.d., ADS,E. (Box-folder 12:84)
      Endorsed: Commo. J. Barron's floating dock.
    - "A Proportion of ammunition, stores, etc. for a 12 & 6 pounder and 5 ½ inch Howitzer," n.d., AD. (Box-folder 12:85)
    - Lists of infantry and artillery officers of Virginia, n.d., AD. (Box-folder 12:86)
    - "A List of Floating Lights on the Coast of England," n.d., AD. (Box-folder 12:87)
  Series 13: Box 13
- Box 13, 1822, n.d. (Box-folder 13:1-6)
  A bound volume printed in Washington City in 1822 by Jacob Gideon, Jr. Proceedings of a Court of Enquiry held at the Navy Yard, Brooklyn, New York upon Capt. James Barron of the United States Navy in May, 1821. 111 pages.
  Notes to the Trial of Commodore Barron, 1808. 8 pages.
  Proceedings of the General Court Martial convened for the trial of Commodore James Barron, Captain Charles Gordon, Mr. Witttam Nook and Capt. John Hall of the United States Ship Chesapeake in the Month of January, 1808. Published by Order of the Navy Department. 496 pages.
  Second Copy of Proceedings of the Court of Enquiry, May 1821 with 3 page autographed introduction [by James Barron].
  Second copy of Notes to the Trial, 1808.
  Autograph volume of a drama, "The Fencing Master's Daughter." 92 pages. unsigned.
  - Bound volume printed in Washington City by Jacob Gideon, Jr. and includes the following three articles, 1822. (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Proceedings of a Court of Enquiry, May 1821, upon Captain James Barron., 1822., 11 pages. PV. (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Notes to the trial of Commodore Barron, 1808, 1822., 8 pages. (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Proceedings of the General Court Martial, January, 1808, Covered for the trial of Commodore James Barron., 1822., 496 pages. (Box-folder 13:1)
  - Proceedings of a Court of Enquiry, held at the Navy Yard, Brooklyn, New York, upon Captain James Barron of the United States Navy in May, 1821., 1822., 111 pages. PV,E. (Box-folder 13:2)
    Autograph endorsement of 3 pages is included.
  - Notes to the trial of Commodore Barron, 1808., n.d., PM. (Box-folder 13:3)
    Includes a long letter from Ro. Saunders, Williamsburg, June 30, 1808, condemning the decision of the Court.
  - "The Fencing Master's Daughter," (a play), n.d., 92 pages. AV. (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Portions of a printed booklet, n.d., Numbered pages included are as follows: 9, 10, 15, 16, 19-22, 25-32, 43-46. PM. (Box-folder 13:5)
    Re: Jamestown celebrations, with remarks made by G. Baidwin and John Madison.
  - Handmade parchment envelope, n.d., AM. (Box-folder 13:6)
    Endorsed, "Mrs. Hope. For my dear Mrs. Hope to keep Memoranda or Letters in."
  Series 14: Box 14
- Box 14, 1818-1955, n.d. (Box-folder 14:1-22)
  Papers connected with the inventions of James Barron, which are not included in previous boxes are collected here. There is an autograph summary statement regarding his inventions and collections of papers concerned with: ship ventilators, log ship, log dock, cork cutter, flag signals, board pump, washing machine, filtering machine, steam ram for battleships, vessel construction, and fan lifting mechanism.
  There are also photographs of: a miniature of James Barron as a young man, made when he was living in Copenhagen; of a painting made of him in a later year; of a miniature of his father, Commo. James Barron, the Elder, of his nephew Commo. Samuel Barron (III), of his daughter, Mrs. George S.(Mary Barron) Blake and his grandson Frank Blake.
  - Papers connected with the inventions of James Barron, 1822-1848, n.d. (Box-folder 14:1-15)
    - A survey of "Inventions and essays on Naval Subjects by Commodore James Barron," n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 14:1)
    - Cork cutter description, [as invented by James Barron], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 14:2)
    - "Original papers relating to the filtering machine" [as invented by James Barron], [1834]., ADr. (Box-folder 14:3)
      See correspondence of February 1834.
    - Flag signals, papers connected with, n.d., 7 items. ADr. (Box-folder 14:4)
      Original letter on signals [by James Barron]. A review of the work done by Barron on signals. Draft of a resolution before the Senate and House of Representatives and the report of the committee on Naval Affairs. Charts and instructions on the use of Flag signals.
    - Log dock descriptions, as invented by James Barron, n.d., 4 pages. ADr. (Box-folder 14:5)
      Sketch included.
    - James Barron "To the Public," n.d., ADrS. (Box-folder 14:6)
      A description of the log ship.
      Typescript copy of the above also included, 1848. Endorsed: "Southern Argus."
    - Description of the valve pump invented by James Barron, n.d., 5 items. ADr. (Box-folder 14:7)
    - Steam ram model photographs, 1827., 3 photographs. Ph. (Box-folder 14:8)
      "Submitted to the Navy Dep't by Commo. James Barron, U.S.N."
    - Re: ships ventilators and bellows invented by James Barron, n.d., 3 items. ADr. (Box-folder 14:9)
    - "Ventilators," n.d., AV. (Box-folder 14:10)
      A 15 page booklet explaining that foul air is the cause of dry rot in the timber of vessels and of sickness among the crew with detailed plans for a more open construction of ships, with ventilators and bellows to change the air.
    - "Plan of a vessel," [as invented by James Barron]. n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 14:11)
    - "Directions for using the washing machine [invented by James Barron], n.d., ADr. (Box-folder 14:12)
    - Patent issued to James Barron for a winch, with drawing, 25 April 1822., PADS. (Box-folder 14:13)
    - Patent issued to James Barron for "a Fan, moved by mechanism, for Bed Chambers, Dining Rooms, Halls, etc.", 5 May 1837., PADS. (Box-folder 14:14)
    - Patent issued to James Barron for "a new and useful improvement in the Washing Machine & for mangling Cloaths," 5 May 1837., PADS. (Box-folder 14:15)
  - Pictorial Images, 1818, n.d. (Box-folder 14:16-22)
  - Photograph of miniature. Item shows either Commo. James Barron, the Elder (Comm. of Virginia Navy in the War of Independence) or his father, Capt. Samuel Barron who commanded at Fort George, n.d., 2 items. Ph,E. (Box-folder 14:16)
  - Photograph of James Barron the Elder's Commission in the State Navy, n.d., Ph,E. (Box-folder 14:17)
    The original image is signed by Thomas Jefferson, as Governor of Virginia, and framed in piece of the 'Constitution.'
  - Photograph of a miniature of Commo. James Barron the Younger, painted by the Court Painter of Denmark, [1818], 2 copies. Ph,E. (Box-folder 14:18)
  - Photograph taken from a portrait of Commo. James Barron, the Younger, n.d., Ph,E. (Box-folder 14:19)
  - Engraving of Commodore James Barron of the U.S. Navy. The engraving was produced by J.W. Steel, from the original painting by Neagle, n.d., Ph. (Box-folder 14:20)
  - Copper plate for printing of portraits of Commodore James Barron, n.d., Copper plate. (Box-folder 14:21)
  - Three photographs of Samuel Barron, Mary Barron, and Frank Blake, n.d., Ph,C, E. (Box-folder 14:22)
    The photographs were enclosed in a cover, endorsed: " 'Uncle' 'Sam' Barron, nephew of Commo. Jas. Barron and son of Commo. Samuel Barron." "Mary Barron, daughter of Commo. James Barron, U.S.N. and wife of Commo. Geo. S. Blake, U.S.N. who remained on the Northern side." "Frank Blake, son of Mary Barron and Geo. S. Blake."
  Series 15: Box 15
- Box 15 (Box-folder 15:1-30)
  A collection of newspaper clippings and complete 4-page newspapers collected by Commo. James Barron, plus a few pieces regarding him collected by his family after his death. Included is one clipping from the Boston Traveler, [1808], in which there is criticism of the sentence of the court martial on The Chesapeake-Leopard Affair. From the Wall Street Reporter of 5 January 1850, little more than a year before his death, there is a long article, "Commodore Barron and the affair of the Chesapeake."
  Regarding the Barron-Decatur duel, there is the "Extra" issued by the Norfolk Beacon, 24 March 1820, and clipping of reports of the duel from 7 other papers. In addition to a newspaper clipping of Mr. Randolph's resolution to Congress on the death of Decatur (which were withdrawn) and an "Indian oration" on the death,there are 6 reports of the duel, two on the return of James Barron to Norfolk after his convalescence in Washington, waiting for the healing of his wound sufficient for him to be moved, one on the action of the Grand Jury investigating the duel, and one editorial opposing the practice of dueling. There are 6 clippings on the Barron-Decatur duel as published in the papers and two on the pamphlet, which was published, containing the correspondence. Finally there is an article from 1850, a year before the death of Barron.
  There are 3 clippings regarding the 1821 Naval Court of Enquiry held on James Barron and 5 clippings, 1947-1955, on the "Rodney Urn." This urn, given by some citizens of Norfolk to Caesar A. Rodney, a famous lawyer, previously U.S. Attorney General, who defended Barron at that Enquiry without pay. The urn, presented to Rodney "for his magnamanimous defense of Commo. Barron," was discovered in Independence Hall, Philadelphia, and was returned to Norfolk in 1954, where it is preserved.
  Complete newspapers included in the collection are a copy of the National Gazette, Philadelphia, in which there is an editorial on the Court of Enquiry which is derogatory to Barron; a copy of the Norfolk and Portsmouth Herald, 4 July 1823, with the obituary of Mrs. Elizabeth Mosely Barron, late wife of James Barron; and a copy of the same paper, 28 August 1824, which contains an account of Barron's invitation to a testimonial dinner in Philadelphia, soon after his reinstatement in the Navy when he took command of the Navy Yard there. He rejected the testimonial as being an inappropriate action at that time. There are ten complete copies of newspapers which reported the visit of General Lafayette to the U.S. in 1824: The American Watchman, Wilmington, of 20 August; the Columbian Observer, Phila., of August 20; the Delaware Gazette, Wilmington, of August 27; the U.S. Gazette, Phila., of 23 and 25 September and 8 October; The New York Gazette, New York, of October; and the Washington Gazette, Washington, D.C. of 11 December. Included also is the complete American Beacon of Norfolk, of 1 May 1851, announcing the death of Commo. Barron on 21 April 1851.
  There is also an editorial from the Norfolk Landmark, founded by James B----- Hope, suggesting that a battleship be names for B-----, and an undated article, written in Philadelphia [1825-1840] under the pseudonym Neptune, by James Barron, predicting that commercial steamships would some day be built 400 feet long to make the journey to Europe in eight days.
  - "Extra" edition of the Norfolk Beacon announcing the duel between Commodore Barron and Commodore Decatur, 24 March 1820., N. (Box-folder 15:1)
    Time of newspaper issue: 2 o'clock P.M. Mailed to Commo. Barron, U.S. Navy, Beal's Hotel, Washington.
  - Six newspaper clippings of reports of the Barron-Decatur duel. 23-25 March 1820., 6 items. NCL. (Box-folder 15:1)
    The newspaper clippings include the following: Georgetown [Metropolitan],23 March 1820; Baltimore Fed. Rep., 23 March 1820, and Baltimore American, 24 March 1820; National Intelligencer, Washington City Gazette, and Georgetown Metropolitan, [22-23 March 1820]; National Messenger, 24 March 1820; Niles Register, 25 March 1820; An one undated account.
  - Report of the resolutions offered by Mr. Randolph in the House of Representatives, [March 1820]., NCl. (Box-folder 15:2)
    Re: mourning for Decatur and withdrawn for lack of support.
  - "Indian Oration of the death of Commo. Decatur." from the National Gazette, n.d., NCl. (Box-folder 15:3)
  - Three reports of the arrangements for the funeral of Commo. Stephen Decatur, 23-25 March 1820., 3 items. NCl. (Box-folder 15:4)
  - Later reactions to the duel, n.d., 3 items. NCl. (Box-folder 15:5)
  - Reports of the return of Commo. Barron to Norfolk after convalescing from his wound, in Washington, 17 April 1820., 2 items. NCl. (Box-folder 15:6)
    Articles taken from The Herald and Norfolk.
  - Reports of the charge delivered by Chief Justice Cranch to the Grand Jury relative to the Barron-Decatur duel, 28 June 1820., 2 items. NCl. (Box-folder 15:7)
    The Herald and the National Intelligencer reports.
  - An editorial on the Barron-Decatur duel, which condemned all duels, [1820]., NCl. (Box-folder 15:8)
  - Newspaper reports of the published correspondence of Barron and Decatur, 8-22 April 1820., 6 items. NCl. (Box-folder 15:9)